Register of the Commission for Relief in Belgium Records, 1914-1930
Hoover Institution Archives
- STANFORD COMMITTEE FOR FRENCH RELIEF FILES, 1919-1920
  - Internal correspondence. Correspondence between the Stanford and Paris offices of the committee, and with the California Committee for Relief in Belgium and France (Box 481)
    - 1917-1918 (pre-history of the organization) (Folder 1)
    - 1919
      - January-April (Folder 2)
      - May-August (Folder 3)
      - September-December (Folder 4)
    - 1920
      - January-March (Folder 5)
      - April-August (Folder 6)
  - Stanford Office general correspondence
    - 1918 (pre-history of the organization) (Folder 7)
    - 1919
      - A (Folder 8)
      - B (Folder 9)
      - C (Folder 10)
      - D (Folder 11)
      - E-G (Folder 12)
      - H-K (Box 482, Folder 1)
      - L (Folder 2)
      - M (Folder 3)
      - N-O (Folder 4)
      - P (Folder 5)
      - R (Folder 6)
      - S (Folder 7)
      - T-W (Folder 8)
    - 1920
      - A-C (Folder 9)
      - D-F (Folder 10)
      - G-L (Folder 11)
      - M-R (Box 483, Folder 1)
      - S-Y (Folder 2)
  - Paris Office general correspondence
    - 1918 (pre-history of the organization)
      - A-J (Folder 3)
      - L-W (Folder 4)
    - 1919
      - A-L (Folder 5)
      - M-W (Folder 6)
    - 1920 (Folder 7)
  - Adoption files, 1919-1920. Note: The principal activity of the committee was provision of financial support to French war orphans through individual "adoption" by American sponsors
    - Lists of orphans and sponsors, 1919-1920 (Folder 8-9)
    - Belgian transfers. Correspondence regarding transfer of sponsorships from Belgian to French children, 1919-1920 (Folder 10)
    - Notes on special cases, n.d. (Folder 11)
    - Individual case files. Correspondence and control sheets, arranged alphabetically by name of child, 1919-1920 (Box 484)
      - A (Folder 1)
      - B-Bl (Folder 2)
      - Bo-Bu (Folder 3)
      - C-Cl (Folder 4)
      - Co-Cu (Folder 5)
      - D-Del (Folder 6)
      - Den-Dev (Folder 7)
      - Di-Du (Folder 8)
      - E-F (Folder 9)
      - G (Folder 10)
      - H (Box 485, Folder 1)
      - I-K (Folder 2)
      - L-Lef (Folder 3)
      - Leg-Lo (Folder 4)
      - M-Ma (Folder 5)
      - Me-Mu (Folder 6)
      - N-O (Folder 7)
      - P-Pe (Folder 8)
      - Pi-Pr (Folder 9)
      - Q-R (Folder 10)
      - S (Box 486, Folder 1)
      - T-U (Folder 2)
      - V-W (Folder 3)
  - Publicity material. Circulars, leaflets and cards, 1919-1920 (Folder 4)
  - Stanford Office financial records, 1919-1920
    - General. Correspondence and memoranda, 1919-1920 (Folder 5)
    - Reports, 1919-1920 (Folder 6)
    - Account books, 1919-1920 (Folder 7-8)
    - Bank statements, 1919-1920 (Folder 9)
    - Deposit slips, 1919-1920 (Folder 10)
    - Canceled checks, 1919-1920 (Folder 11)
    - Receipts, 1919-1920 (Folder 12)
  - Paris Office financial records, 1918-1920
    - General. Correspondence and lists, 1919-1920 (Folder 13)
    - Reports, 1919-1920 (Folder 14)
    - Account books, 1919-1920 (Box 487, Folder 1-3)
    - Disbursement journals
      - 1918-1920 (Folder 4)
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 5)
    - Miscellany, 1919-1920 (Folder 6)
  - Related organizational files, 1916-1917
    - California Special North of France Fund. Correspondence and receipts
      - 1916 (Folder 7)
      - 1917
        - February-March (Folder 8)
        - April-May (Folder 9)
        - June (Folder 10)
        - July-September (Folder 11)
    - Commission Californienne pour la Reconstruction des Villages Français Détruits par la Guerre. Correspondence and minutes, 1916-1917 (Folder 12)
  - Address card file for orphans and sponsors, n.d. (Box 488)
- UNITED STATES. FOOD ADMINISTRATION. MARINE TRANSPORTATION DIVISION FILES, 1918-1919.
  Primarily from files of Wallace H. Foster and Golden W. Bell, successive officials of the New York City Office in charge of arranging shipments for the Commission for Relief in Belgium
  - Intra-office correspondence. Memoranda exchanged between Wallace H. Foster and Golden W. Bell, on the one hand, and other members of the New York City Office, on the other hand, 1918-1919 (Box 489)
    - Barnes, Julius H., 1918-1919 (Folder 1)
    - Beatty, William, 1918-1919 (Folder 2)
    - Brumell, Mr., 1918-1919 (Folder 3)
    - Davis, H. C., 1918-1919 (Folder 4)
    - Doe, C. P., 1918-1919 (Folder 5)
    - Durbaum, George, 1918-1919 (Folder 6)
    - Gerks, Ben, 1918-1919 (Folder 7)
    - Hall, G. Roy, 1918-1919 (Folder 8)
    - Hitchcock, Mr., 1918-1919 (Folder 9)
    - O'Brien, A. D., 1919 (Folder 10)
    - Rick, Mr., 1918-1919 (Folder 11)
    - Sherman, Roger, 1919 (Folder 12)
    - Simpson, Mr., 1919 (Folder 13)
    - Smith, H. M., 1918-1919 (Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous, 1919 (Folder 15)
  - Intra-agency correspondence. Correspondence between the New York City office and other offices of the Food Administration, 1918-1919
    - Baltimore (Md.) Office, 1918-1919 (Folder 16)
    - Philadelphia (Pa.) Office, 1918-1919 (Folder 17)
    - Portland (Ore.) Office (Max Houser), 1918-1919 (Folder 18)
    - San Francisco (Calif.) Office (R. A. Lewin), 1918 (Folder 19)
    - Washington (D.C.) Office, 1918-1919
      - Fletcher, J. D.
        - 1918
          - June-September (Folder 20)
          - October-December (Folder 21)
        - 1919 (Box 490, Folder 1)
      - Gray, Prentiss N.
        - 1918
          - June-September (Folder 2)
          - October-December (Folder 3)
        - 1919 (Folder 4)
      - Hoover, Herbert, 1919 (Folder 5)
      - Plummer, H. P., 1918 (Folder 6)
  - General correspondence, 1918-1919
    - General, 1918-1919
      - A-H (Folder 7)
      - I-P (Folder 8)
      - S-Y (Folder 9)
    - American Linseed Company, 1918 (Folder 10)
    - Benham and Boyesen, Inc., 1918 (Folder 11)
    - Birt and Company, 1918-1919 (Folder 12)
    - Central Timber Export Company, 1918-1919 (Folder 13)
    - Commission for Relief in Belgium
      - 1917 (Folder 14)
      - 1918
        - January-September (Folder 15)
        - October-December (Folder 16)
      - 1919 (Box 491, Folder 1)
      - 1920 (Folder 2)
    - Furness, Withy and Company, 1918 (Folder 3)
    - James Arkell and Company, 1918-1919 (Folder 4)
    - New York (N.Y.) Department of Docks and Ferries, 1918 (Folder 5)
    - Norton, Lilly and Company, 1918-1919 (Folder 6)
    - Peters, White and Company, 1918 (Folder 7)
    - Shipping Control Committee, 1918-1919 (Folder 8)
    - Sidnam Lighterage and Transportation Company. Includes bills
      - 1918 (Folder 9)
      - 1919
        - January-February (Folder 10)
        - March (Folder 11)
        - April (Folder 12)
        - May (Folder 13)
  - Daily shipping reports, 1918-1919
    - Grain ships in port
      - 1918 (Folder 14)
      - 1919 (Folder 15)
    - Maritime miscellany, 1918-1919 (Box 492, Folder 1)
    - Steamers sailed/Steamers in port, 1918 (Folder 2)
  - Port position sheets, 1919
    - February-March (Folder 3)
    - April-May (Folder 4)
  - Shipping control sheets
    - 1918 (Folder 5)
    - 1919 (Folder 6)
  - Shipping letters (numerical series originating in Commission for Relief in Belgium London Office), 1918-1919 (Folder 7)
  - Subject file. Correspondence and memoranda, 1918-1919
    - Alcor (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 8)
    - Almora (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 9)
    - American Relief Administration ships, 1919 (Folder 10)
    - Arkansas (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 11)
    - Asta (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 12)
    - Automobiles, 1919 (Folder 13)
    - Ballast, 1918-1919 (Folder 14)
    - Belmont (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 15)
    - Bills. Correspondence and memoranda regarding (Box 493)
      - 1918 (Folder 1)
      - 1919 (Folder 2)
    - Bones, South American, 1918 (Folder 3)
    - Brazil--Exports and imports, 1917-1918 (Folder 4)
    - Buda II (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 5)
    - Bunkers, 1918 (Folder 6)
    - Clothing, 1918-1919 (Folder 7)
    - Coffee. Includes minutes of the Coffee Committee on Freights and Licenses
      - 1918
        - May-June (Folder 8)
        - July-December (Folder 9)
      - 1919 (Folder 10)
    - Concordia (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 11)
    - European Food Relief Shipping Program, 1918-1919 (Folder 12)
    - European Food Relief Shipping Program, Northern, 1918-1919 (Folder 13)
    - European Food Relief Shipping Program, Southern, 1918-1919 (Folder 14)
    - Flour, 1918 (Folder 15)
    - Flour, Cuban, 1918-1919 (Folder 16)
    - Flour, Pacific Coast, 1918-1919 (Box 494, Folder 1)
    - J. Aron and Company, 1918 (Folder 2)
    - Korsnaes (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 3)
    - Leases. Correspondence and memoranda regarding, 1918-1919 (Folder 4)
    - Longshoremen. Labor agreement, 1918 (Folder 5)
    - Marga (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 6)
    - Mathilda (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 7)
    - Newa (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 8)
    - Oakland (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 9)
    - Ossinike (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 10)
    - Packinghouse products, 1919 (Folder 11)
    - Protector (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 12)
    - Rails, 1918-1919 (Folder 13)
    - Rice, Puerto Rican, 1918-1919 (Folder 14)
    - Salmon (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 15)
    - Salt, 1918 (Folder 16)
    - Sugar beet seed, 1918 (Folder 17)
    - Swedish shipping, 1917-1918 (Folder 18)
    - Vegetable oils, 1918 (Folder 19)
    - Ventura (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 20)
    - Wheat, Argentine, 1918 (Folder 21)
    - Wheat, Australian, 1918-1919 (Folder 22)
    - Willis A. Holden (Steamship), 1918 (Folder 23)
- NATIONAL COMMITTEE FOR RELIEF IN BELGIUM FILES, 1915-1919
  - Chronological file. Correspondence and memoranda, 1915-1917 (Box 495, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of second annual meeting, 1917 (Folder 2)
  - Financial records, 1918-1919
    - Delivery control records, 1918-1919 (Folder 3)
    - Dispatch and receipt records, 1918-1919 (Folder 4)
    - Invoices, 1918-1919 (Folder 5)
    - Order control records, 1918-1919 (Folder 6)
    - Orders, 1918-1919 (Folder 7)
    - Receipts, 1918-1919 (Folder 8)
  - Shipping records, 1918-1919 (Folder 9)
  - Publications, 1915-1919 (Box 496)
    - How Belgium Is Fed, 1915 (Folder 1)
    - In Belgium under German Rule, 1916 (Folder 2)
    - Annual Report. Second, 1917 (Folder 3)
    - National Committee for Relief in Belgium, 1915-1919: The Record of British Empire Benevolence on Behalf of Those Who Remained in Belgium during the War, 1919 (Folder 4)
- COMITE NATIONAL DE SECOURS ET D'ALIMENTATION FILES, 1914-1920
  - Chronological file. Correspondence, memoranda, reports, agreements, instructions, proclamations, and miscellany (Box 497)
    - 1914
      - August-October (Folder 1)
      - November-December (Folder 2)
    - 1915
      - January-June (Folder 3)
      - July-December (Folder 4)
    - 1916
      - January-May (Folder 5)
      - June-August (Folder 6)
      - September (Folder 7)
      - October-November (Box 498, Folder 1)
      - December (Folder 2)
    - 1917
      - January-May (Folder 3)
      - June (Folder 4)
      - July-September (Folder 5)
      - October-December (Folder 6)
    - 1918-1920 (Folder 7)
    - Undated (Folder 8-9)
  - Financial records, 1915-1920 (Box 499)
    - Current account statements, 1915-1920 (Folder 1)
    - Current account reconciliation statements, 1916-1920 (Folder 2)
    - Benevolent, merchandise and commercial exchange account statements, 1915-1919 (Folder 3)
    - Balance sheets and control statements
      - 1915-1916 (Folder 4)
      - 1917-1919 (Folder 5)
    - Cloth orders, 1915-1916. Includes specifications (Folder 6)
  - Publications, 1914-1918 (Box 500)
    - Rapport du Comité exécutif
      - 1914 December. Typed English translation only (Folder 1)
      - 1915 February (Folder 2)
    - Assurance couvrant le transport des marchandises importées pour l'approvisionnement des provinces, 1915 (Folder 3)
    - Principales garanties données par les autorités allemandes et instructions envoyées par le Gouverneur Général aux Gouverneurs en province et aux autorités militaires des inspections d'étapes, 1915 (Folder 4)
    - Recueil des règlements et instructions générales
      - First edition, 1917 (Folder 5)
      - Second edition, 1918 (Folder 6)
    - Principes d'alimentation et conseils sur la préparation économique des aliments, n.d. (Folder 7)
  - Sample forms, n.d. (Folder 8)
  - Provincial committee meeting minutes (minutes of meetings of representatives from the various provinces)
    - 1914 (Folder 9)
    - 1915
      - January (Folder 10)
      - February (Folder 11)
      - March (Box 501, Folder 1)
      - April (Folder 2)
      - November-December (Folder 3)
    - 1916 (Folder 4)
    - 1917
      - February (Folder 5)
      - March-April (Folder 6)
    - 1918-1919 (Folder 7)
  - Provincial committee reports
    - Antwerp, 1914-1917 (Folder 8)
    - Brabant, 1914-1915 (Folder 9)
    - Brussels. Includes minutes (Box 502)
      - 1914-1915 January (Folder 1)
      - 1915 February-June (Folder 2)
    - East Flanders, 1914-1915 (Folder 3)
    - Hainaut
      - 1914-1915 (Folder 4)
      - 1918-1919 (Folder 5)
    - Liège (Box 503)
      - 1914-1915 August (Folder 1)
      - 1915 December (Folder 2)
      - 1916-1919 (Folder 3)
    - Limbourg, 1915 (Folder 4)
    - Luxembourg
      - 1914 (Folder 5)
      - 1915 (Folder 6)
    - Namur, 1914-1915 (Folder 7)
    - West Flanders, 1915 (Folder 8)
- COMITE D'ALIMENTATION DU NORD DE LA FRANCE FILES, 1915-1920
  - Chronological file. Correspondence, memoranda and reports (Box 504)
    - 1915
      - February-August (Folder 1)
      - September-November (Folder 2)
      - December (Folder 3)
    - 1916
      - January-June (Folder 4)
      - July-August (Folder 5)
      - September-December (Folder 6)
    - 1917
      - January-May (Folder 7)
      - June-December (Box 505, Folder 1)
    - 1918 (Folder 2)
    - 1919-1920 (Folder 3)
    - Undated (Folder 4)
  - Conférence du Ravitaillement proceedings
    - 1918
      - January-March (Folder 5)
      - April-May (Folder 6)
      - June-September (Folder 7)
    - 1919 (Folder 8)
  - Map of reconquered territory, 1917 (Box 506, Folder 1)
  - Publications, 1915-1920
    - Aux maires, aux institutrices, aux mères de familles, 1915. Includes typed English translation (Folder 2)
    - Rapport sur les opérations de l'année 1917, 1918 (Folder 3-5)
    - Rapport final sur les opérations du Comité: Annexes: Supplement, 1920 (Folder 6)
    - Instructions aux municipalités en ce qui concerne la distribution de pain par locaux communaux, n.d. (Box 507, Folder 1)
    - Note sur l'organisation générale, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - District reports, 1915-1917
    - Charleville, 1915-1917 (Folder 3)
    - Lille, 1915 (Folder 4)
    - St. Quentin, 1915-1916 (Folder 5)
    - Valenciennes
      - 1915 (Folder 6)
      - 1916 (Folder 7)
    - Vervins, 1915
      - May-June (Folder 8)
      - July (Folder 9)
      - August-September (Folder 10)
- COMITE D'ASSISTANCE DES REGIONS LIBEREES FILES, 1919-1924
  - Chronological file. Correspondence, memoranda and press releases (Box 508)
    - 1919 (Folder 1)
    - 1920 (Folder 2)
    - 1921 (Folder 3)
    - 1922-1924 (Folder 4)
  - Reports, 1919-1921 (Folder 5)
  - Monthly statistical reports, 1921-1923 (Folder 6)
  - Financial records, 1919-1922
    - Donation correspondence, 1920-1922 (Folder 7)
    - Accounts
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 8)
      - 1921-1922 (Box 509, Folder 1)
  - Subject file. Correspondence, reports, memoranda, and printed matter, 1920-1923
    - Child welfare, 1920-1922 (Folder 2)
    - Child welfare exhibit, Lille, 1921 (Folder 3)
    - Colonies Scolaires, 1920 (Folder 4)
    - Consultations de Nourissons
      - General, 1920-1921 (Folder 5)
      - Reports, 1920
        - July (Folder 6)
        - August (Folder 7)
        - November (Folder 8)
      - Letters of appreciation, 1920 (Folder 9)
    - Fatherless Children of France, 1921 (Folder 10)
    - Open Air Schools, 1920 (Folder 11)
    - Tuberculosis hospital (Proposed), 1920 (Folder 12)
    - University of Labor (Proposed), 1920-1923 (Folder 13)
- COMITE HISPANO-NEERLANDAIS POUR LA PROTECTION DU RAVITAILLEMENT FILES, 1917-1919
  - Chronological file. Correspondence, memoranda and minutes (Box 510)
    - 1915 (pre-history of the organization) (Folder 1)
    - 1917
      - February-May (Folder 2)
      - June (Folder 3)
      - July (Folder 4)
      - August (Folder 5)
      - September-October (Folder 6)
      - November (Folder 7)
      - December (Folder 8)
    - 1918
      - January (Folder 9)
      - February-March (Folder 10)
      - April-May (Folder 11)
      - June-July (Box 511, Folder 1)
      - August-September (Folder 2)
      - October-December (Folder 3)
    - 1919 (Folder 4)
  - Reports
    - 1917
      - September 1 (Folder 5)
      - October 1 (Folder 6)
      - November 1 (Folder 7)
      - December 1 (Folder 8)
    - 1918
      - January 1 (Folder 9)
      - February 1 (Folder 10)
      - February 4 (Folder 11)
      - March 1 (Box 512, Folder 1)
      - March 11 (Folder 2)
      - March 18 (Folder 3)
      - April 1 (Folder 4)
      - May 1 (Folder 5)
      - June 1 (Folder 6)
      - July 1 (Folder 7)
      - August 1 (Box 513, Folder 1)
      - September 1 (Folder 2)
      - October 1 (Folder 3)
      - October 26 (Folder 4)
      - November 1 (Folder 5)
      - November 19 (Folder 6)
  - Statistical reports, n.d.
    - Thefts and missing foodstuffs
      - Belgium (Folder 7)
      - France (Box 514, Folder 1)
    - Vital statistics of occupied regions
      - Belgium (Folder 2)
      - France (Folder 3)
- COMITATO NAZIONALE ITALIANO PER I SOCCORSI ALLE VITTIME DELLA GUERRA NEL BELGIO FILES, 1914-1916
  - Chronological file. Correspondence and clippings, 1914-1916 (Box 515, Folder 1)
  - Report, 1916 (Folder 2)
- BELGIAN GRATITUDE FILE, 1914-1918
  - Artwork (Box 516)
    - Drawings and paintings (Folder 1-12)
    - Images of Belgian royal family (Box 517, Folder 1-16)
    - Paper cut-outs (Box 518, Folder 1-7)
    - Paper cut-outs (Box 519)
    - Paper cut-outs (Box 520, Folder 1-3)
  - Books (Folder 4)
  - Business cards (Folder 5)
  - Calendars (Folder 6-7)
  - Embroidery (Folder 8-10)
  - Letters (Box 521)
    - General
      - General (Folder 1-6)
      - General (Box 522, Folder 1-6)
      - General (Box 523, Folder 1-4)
      - Group letters from communities (Folder 5)
      - Translations from French (Folder 6-8)
    - Children's letters (Box 524)
      - General (Folder 1-8)
      - General (Box 525)
        - General (Folder 1-2)
        - Christmas greetings (Folder 3-6)
        - Photographs attached (Box 526, Folder 1-6)
      - Addressed to Woodrow Wilson (Folder 7)
  - Portfolios (Box 527, Folder 1-14)
  - Postcards. Includes letters (Box 528)
    - Hand painted (Folder 1-6)
    - Printed (Box 529, Folder 1-7)
  - Stamps (Folder 8)
- PRINTED MATTER COLLECTED BY THE COMMISSION FOR RELIEF IN BELGIUM, 1911-1921
  - General - History and organization (Box 530, Folder 1)
  - Countries
    - Austria. Österreichisches statistisches Handbuch, XXXV Jahrgang, 1916-1917, K. K. Statistische Zentralkommission, Vienna, 1918 (Folder 2)
    - Belgium
      - General
        - General (Folder 3)
        - Country description (Folder 4-5)
        - German occupation (Box 531)
          - English (Folder 1)
          - French
            - General (Folder 2-3)
            - Cinquante mois d'occupation allemande
              - 1914-1915, 1916 (Folder 4)
              - 1917, 1918 (Folder 5)
            - Revue belge des livres, documents et archives de la guerre 1914-1918, 1918 (Box 532, Folder 1)
      - Brochures (Folder 2-3)
      - Bulletins
        - General (Folder 4-5)
        - Bulletin d'informations de presse, 1919 (Folder 6)
        - Bulletin de l'office des régions dévastées
          - 1919 (Folder 7)
          - 1920 (Folder 8)
          - 1921 (Folder 9)
        - Informations belges
          - 1917 (Folder 10)
          - 1918 (Box 533, Folder 1)
        - Oeuvre nationale de l'enfance, nos. 2-5, 1919-1920 (Folder 2)
        - Société générale de Belgique: Compte rendu présenté à l'assemblée générale des actionnaires, 1918 (Folder 3)
      - Maps. Carte des chemins de fer, routes et voies navigables de la Belgique, 1911 (Folder 4)
      - Newspapers
        - L'invasion. Special edition of La gazette de Charleroi on the day of the German invasion, 1914 (Folder 5)
        - La libre Belgique, 1915-1916 (Folder 6-7)
      - Reports, Government
        - English language
          - General (Folder 8)
          - Reply to the German White Book of 10th of May 1915, Die Völkerische Führung des belgischen Volkskrieges, 1918 (Folder 9)
          - Reports on the Violation of the Rights of Nations and of the Laws and Customs of War in Belgium, n.d. (Folder 10)
        - French language
          - General (Folder 11)
          - Economic conditions (Box 534, Folder 1)
          - Social conditions (Folder 2)
    - Canada
      - Periodicals. Pro Belgica: The Canadian Friend of Belgium, 1918 (in English and French) (Folder 3)
      - Reports. Relief Work for the Victims of the War in Belgium, 1915, 1917 (Folder 4)
    - France
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Books. L'effort du ravitaillement français, pendant la guerre et pour la paix, 1914-1920, n.d. (Folder 6)
      - Brochures
        - Albert I-er: Roi de Belgique, 1915 (Folder 7)
        - The Call of the Perishing: An Account of Conditions Among Serbian Refugees in France and the Means of Relieving Them, American Red Cross, 1918 (Folder 8)
      - Bulletins
        - Bulletin de Lille, 1916 May 25 (Folder 9)
        - Bulletin quotidien de presse étrangère, 1919 (Folder 10)
        - L'âme belge, 1917 (Folder 11)
    - Germany (Box 535)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Newspapers. Daily American Newspaper, American Relief Commission, Berlin, 1914, nos. 1-3, 12 (Folder 2)
      - Reports, Government
        - European Politics during the Decade before the War as Described by Belgian Diplomatists: Reports of the Belgian Representatives in Berlin, London and Paris to the Ministers of Foreign Affairs in Brussels, 1905-1914, 1915 (Folder 3)
        - The Case of Belgium: German Disclosure of Secret Belgian Government Correspondence with England before the War, n.d. (Folder 4)
    - Great Britain
      - Books
        - Belgium and Germany: Texts and Documents, 1915 (Folder 5)
        - British and German Ideals: The Meaning of the War, n.d. (Folder 6)
      - Brochures (Folder 7)
      - Clippings. American Relief Committee, London Division, 1914 (Folder 8)
      - Newspapers
        - General (Folder 9)
        - The Times, 1915 (Folder 10)
      - Reports, Government
        - General
          - Correspondence Respecting the Relief of Allied Territories in the Occupation of the Enemy, 1916 (Folder 11)
          - Departmental Committee on Prices: Increase of Prices of Commodities since the Beginning of the War, 1917 (Folder 12)
        - Internees and prisoners of war (Folder 13-14)
    - Switzerland
      - Brochures
        - Pendant la grande guerre: L'hospitalisation des enfants belges en Suisse et l'aide américaine, 1920 (Folder 15)
        - Rapport général de l'oeuvre des réfugiés belges en Suisse, 1918 (Folder 16)
      - Bulletins. The Messenger to the Prisoners of War, 1918 (Folder 17)
    - United States (Box 536)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Atlases. Reynold's After-War Atlas and Gazetteer of the World, 1919 (Folder 2)
      - Brochures
        - General (Folder 3)
        - Hoover, Herbert - Biographical material (Folder 4)
      - Bulletins
        - American Bulletin, by American Citizens Committee, London, 1914 (Folder 5)
        - Belgian Bulletin, by Belgian Official Information Service, 1918-1919 (Folder 6)
        - Belgian Official Information Service, 1918, February-April (Folder 7)